<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Home Page on Omers Blog</title><link>https://omers.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Home Page on Omers Blog</description><image><url>https://omers.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url><link>https://omers.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link></image><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 14:13:19 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://omers.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Best practices for advanced serverless developers</title><link>https://omers.github.io/docs/aws/best-practices-for-serverless-developers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 08:46:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://omers.github.io/docs/aws/best-practices-for-serverless-developers/</guid><description>re:invent 2022 recorded session This session provides architectural best practices, optimizations, and useful cheat codes that you can use to build secure, high-scale, and high-performance serverless applications and uses real customer scenarios to illustrate the benefits.</description></item><item><title>Teleport Access and Authorization</title><link>https://omers.github.io/docs/teleport/access-and-authorization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 14:48:17 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://omers.github.io/docs/teleport/access-and-authorization/</guid><description>Teleport has a strong RBAC system that allows to grant access to specific resources.
In order to setup your environment, You need to do some preperations:
Define what are the Groups in your organization Define which access each group needs, For example:
Developers group needs access to Grafana and server Superset Decide how to label each server / resource, and assign the labels to each resource Deinfe the policy that grants the access to the resources kind: role version: v5 metadata: name: Developers description: Developers Team Role spec: allow: logins: [&amp;#39;admin&amp;#39;] node_labels: &amp;#39;type&amp;#39;: &amp;#39;Grafana&amp;#39; &amp;#39;type&amp;#39;: &amp;#39;Superset&amp;#39;</description></item><item><title>Data Protection and Anonymization</title><link>https://omers.github.io/docs/data/anonymization/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 09:14:01 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://omers.github.io/docs/data/anonymization/</guid><description>Mining health data can lead to faster medical decisions, improvement in the quality of treatment, disease prevention, reduced cost, and it drives innovative solutions within the healthcare sector.
However, health data is highly sensitive and subject to regulations such as the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), which aims to ensure patient&amp;rsquo;s privacy.
Anonymization or removal of patient identifiable information, though the most conventional way, is the first important step to adhere to the regulations and incorporate privacy concerns.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Resources Governance</title><link>https://omers.github.io/docs/cloud-management/cloud-resources-governance/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 09:56:30 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://omers.github.io/docs/cloud-management/cloud-resources-governance/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Cloud Resources Dashboards</title><link>https://omers.github.io/docs/cloud-management/cloud-resources-dashboards/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 09:56:20 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://omers.github.io/docs/cloud-management/cloud-resources-dashboards/</guid><description>During the lifecycle of a company, we are required to have an assets inventory.
The process of having an asset inventory contains few steps.
CloudQuery As the tool that scrapes AWS and gather all the information, We will use CloudQuery
TimescaleDB Apache Superset</description></item><item><title>Cloudquery</title><link>https://omers.github.io/docs/monitoring/cloudquery/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 16:37:30 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://omers.github.io/docs/monitoring/cloudquery/</guid><description/></item><item><title>N8n</title><link>https://omers.github.io/docs/automation/n8n/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 14:37:48 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://omers.github.io/docs/automation/n8n/</guid><description/></item><item><title>OpenSSL Generate self signed certificate</title><link>https://omers.github.io/docs/automation/generate-self-signed-cert/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 14:37:48 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://omers.github.io/docs/automation/generate-self-signed-cert/</guid><description>This is a one liner on how to create SSL Self signed certificate with OpenSSL
openssl req -new -newkey rsa:4096 -days 365 \ -nodes -x509 -keyout server.key -out server.crt</description></item><item><title>Loki Log based metrics a.k.a logs2metrics</title><link>https://omers.github.io/docs/monitoring/loki/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 19:09:12 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://omers.github.io/docs/monitoring/loki/</guid><description>Loki is a datastore optimized for efficiently holding log data.
The efficient indexing of log data distinguishes Loki from other logging systems. Unlike other logging systems, a Loki index is built from labels, leaving the original log message unindexed.
The Basic native tool to send data to Loki, is Promtail
A sample config file for Loki might seen like the follows:
server: http_listen_port: 0 grpc_listen_port: 0 positions: filename: /tmp/positions.yaml clients: - url: https://your.</description></item><item><title>Prometheus Common Queries</title><link>https://omers.github.io/cheatsheet/prometheus/common-queries/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 09:15:49 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://omers.github.io/cheatsheet/prometheus/common-queries/</guid><description>Quantiles from histograms 90th percentile request latency over last 5 minutes, for every label dimension:
histogram_quantile(0.9, rate(api_duration_seconds_bucket[5m])) Rates of increase for counters Per-second rate of increase, averaged over last 5 minutes: rate(demo_api_request_duration_seconds_count[5m]) Per-second rate of increase, calculated over last two samples in a 1-minute time window irate(demo_api_request_duration_seconds_count[1m]) Absolute increase over last hour: increase(demo_api_request_duration_seconds_count[1h]) Aggregating over time Average within each series over a 5-minute period avg_over_time(go_goroutines[5m]) Get the maximum for each series over a one-day period max_over_time(process_resident_memory_bytes[1d]) Count the number of samples for each series over a 5-minute period count_over_time(process_resident_memory_bytes[5m])</description></item><item><title>YOLO — You only look once</title><link>https://omers.github.io/docs/ai/yolov/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 08:47:06 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://omers.github.io/docs/ai/yolov/</guid><description>YOLOv5 🚀 is a family of object detection architectures and models pretrained on the COCO dataset, and represents Ultralytics open-source research into future vision AI methods, incorporating lessons learned and best practices evolved over thousands of hours of research and development.
The project source code can be found Here</description></item><item><title>Python Nlp Libraries</title><link>https://omers.github.io/docs/ai/python-nlp-libraries/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 14:37:22 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://omers.github.io/docs/ai/python-nlp-libraries/</guid><description>Natural language processing (NLP) is a field that focuses on making natural human language usable by computer programs. NLTK, or Natural Language Toolkit, is a Python package that you can use for NLP.
A lot of the data that you could be analyzing is unstructured data and contains human-readable text. Before you can analyze that data programmatically, you first need to preprocess it. In this tutorial, you’ll take your first look at the kinds of text preprocessing tasks you can do with NLTK so that you’ll be ready to apply them in future projects.</description></item><item><title>Python Scikit Learn</title><link>https://omers.github.io/docs/ai/slearn/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 14:37:22 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://omers.github.io/docs/ai/slearn/</guid><description>Scikit-learn is an open source machine learning library that supports supervised and unsupervised learning. It also provides various tools for model fitting, data preprocessing, model selection, model evaluation, and many other utilities.</description></item></channel></rss>